<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Jamel M. Thomas</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Jamel M. Thomas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboards with Flexdashboard</title>
      <link>/blog/time-series-for-avg-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/time-series-for-avg-house/</guid>
      <description>Flex Dashboards Everyone knows high-level languages are wonderful. The issues of yester-year are long gone; we no longer have to build dashboards from scratch. Being able to query data, and display directly thorugh R is here, and I don’t see it going anywhere anytime soon.
Flexdashboard is an open source package in R that allows users to display dashboards directly in browser. It also has publishing support through RStudio. Assuming you have moderate traffic (like me), it’s perfect!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotly for College Analysis</title>
      <link>/blog/plotly-text-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/plotly-text-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Plotly for College Analysis In this post, we explore open college data. This dataset includes the name of the college, the aggregated number of people who passed a particular subject by transfer level and race.
Let’s read out data and take a look:
There is a wonderful package called DT that creates interactive plots in HTML. It even comes with a search feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in R Markdown?</title>
      <link>/blog/python-in-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/python-in-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>Python in R Markdown R Markdown supports Python integration with the package reticulate.The nice thing about R Markdown is that it is the first scripting language I have ever learned. Therefore, I am almost too comfortable with it. It is my go to for most of my project because it’s so easy to get a proof of concept with new ideas. The downfall of it - until now - is that I was unaware that we could use PYTHON IN R MARKDOWN!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL, Databases &amp; R</title>
      <link>/blog/sql-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/sql-and-r/</guid>
      <description>SQL SQL is a querying language used to manipulate databases. On its own, it is a powerful tool in any Data Scientist’s toolbox. When you pair SQL with R (or Python), you have indespensible foundations to conduct even the basic analytics. This is not so much a lesson on SQL, but a lesson on connecting SQL with R via various packages. Moreover, we will use the packages dbplyr and dplyr to manipulate the datasets in a later blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where have I been?</title>
      <link>/blog/where-have-i-been/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/where-have-i-been/</guid>
      <description>Where Am I from? I began this blog in the summer of 2018, mostly because I needed a place to put all of the things I do for fun. What better way than to build your own webssite and put all that crap there?? I have come across this beautiful post from the D3js website. It creates a plot of where the author has been.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>